<data>
<title>Agriculture</title><text>The purposeful tending of crops and livestock in order to produce food and fiber, this is what MOST clearly moved the human species, led to the massive explosion in population, was triggered by the end of an ice age.</text>
<title>Akkadians</title><text>this civilization included Semitic people living north of Sumeria; conquered Sumeria; united city-states of Mesopotamia; first empire in history; established by Sargon the Great</text>
<title>Anyang</title><text>Shang's oldest and most important building; one of the capitals; built of wood; located in forest, wa also the capital.</text>
<title>Babylonian Empire</title><text>Unified all of Mesopotamia circa 1,800 BCE; collapsed due to foreign invasion circa 1,600 BCE</text>
<title>Back Problems</title><text>Is a problem caused largely by evolutionary history, came about because of upright structure.</text>
<title>Barbarian</title><text>A term coined by the ancient greek to disparage those that did not speak their language, throughout history it has changed from being a cultural construct( Greeks, Romans) to a social and racial one (Nazi Germany, Dark Age Europe) etc etc.</text>
<title>Bronze Age</title><text>A period of human culture between the Stone Age and the Iron Age, characterized by the use of weapons and implements made of BRONZE. From 4000 BCE to 1500 BCE when Iron replaced it.</text>
<title>Catal Huyuk</title><text>One of the world's first Neolithic cities(founded in 7000 BCE, the remains of this large city were found in 1958 in modern Turkey. Houses were largely made of mub brick set in timber frames. Worship of a "Mother Goddess". Was actually larger in population than Jericho and had a greater degree of social stratification.</text>
<title>City-state</title><text>An independent, self-governing city; a form of political organization typical of Mesopotamian civilizations; consisted of agricultural hinterlands ruled by an urban-based king.</text>
<title>Civilization</title><text>Socities distinguised by a reliance on sedentary agriculture, ability to produce food surpluses, and the existence of non- farming elites, as well as merchant and manufacturing groups. Also involves the formation of formal political ties or states , as opposed to a dependence on family or tribal ties.</text>
<title>Copper</title><text>The first metal that people learned to use and work with, soon replaced by the stronger bronze. An early example of humans(and civilizations) impact on the enviroment is exhibited when the large scale production of copper along the Danube Valley led to extensive deforestation that ended up depleting the fuel supply, and the industry collapsed around 3000 BCE.</text>
<title>Cultures</title><text>Systems of belief that help explain the environment and set up rules for various kinds of social behavior. Emerged in the late Paleolithic and was also accompioned by the rapid spread of speech(languages)</text>
<title>Cuneiform</title><text>a system of writing used in ancient Mesopotamia(around 3500 BCE) , in which wedge-shaped characters were produced b pressing a stylus into a soft clay tablet, which was then baked or otherwise hardened. Early writing such as this enabled socities to tax more efficently, make contracts, treaties, and generate an intellectual climate which promoted "rationality"</text>
<title>Domestication</title><text>The conscious manipulation of plant and animal species by humans in order to sustain themselves. Along with agriculture it effectively changed the roles and relationships between men and women and patterns of childbearing , leading to social stratification, political organizations, expression, and larger more lethal war.</text>
<title>Dravidians</title><text>one of the main groups of people in India; probably descended from the Indus River culture that flourished at the dawn of Indian civilization over 4,000 yrs. ago</text>
<title>Eugene Dubois</title><text>He uncovered what he believed to be the remains of a human ancestor. He named his find Homo erectus, meaning human who stands upright. It was nicknamed Java Man</text>
<title>Hammurabi</title><text>Amorite ruler of Babylon (r. 1792-1750 B.C.E.). He conquered many city-states in southern and northern Mesopotamia and is best known for a code of laws, inscribed on a black stone pillar, illustrating the principles to be used in legal cases. Boasted that " to promot the welfar of the people, I Hammurabi, the devout, god fearing prince, cause justice to prevail in the land by destroying the wicked and eveil, that the strong might not opress the weak"</text>
<title>Harappa</title><text>Site of one of the great cities of the Indus Valley civilization of the third millennium B.C.E. It was located on the northwest frontier of the zone of cultivation , and may have been a center for the acquisition of raw materials. Was laid out on a planned grid pattern.Language of the civilization has NOT been deciphered. Part of Indus River Valley Civilization</text>
<title>Harappan Culture</title><text>Existed three millennia ago in the age of bronze and copper. Advanced and developed for its time. Traded with the Persian Gulf and Mesopotamia. Believed in life after death but there was no concept of reincarnation. Also known as the Indus Valley Civilization.</text>
<title>Homo Erectus</title><text>The humanoid species that developed a larger brain capacity, erect stance(leading to better tool use) emerging between 500,000 and 750,000 ears ago. First developed a nd spread in Africa, then to Asia and Europe, reaching a population size of perhaps 1.5 million 100,000 years ago. Now Extinct</text>
<title>Homo Sapiens</title><text>The newest human breed, which emerged as the most successful(and therefore survived), and of which ALL humans in the world are descendants.</text>
<title>hunting and gathering</title><text>The process of living that involves hunting for meat, gathering edible produce, and traveling frequently.</text>
<title>Ideographic</title><text>Pictographic characters grouped together to create new concepts; typical of Chinese writing.</text>
<title>Indus River Valley</title><text>located in modern Pakistan; also known as Harappan Culture (including Mohenjo-Daro); highly advanced organized: sewer system, grid streets, uniform building construction, all examples of centralized government, home of dravidians., Language of the civilization has NOT been deciphered.</text>
<title>Java Man</title><text>A homo erectus discovered by Dutch physician and anatomist Eugene Dubois in 1891 in JAVA Indonesia,</text>
<title>Kush</title><text>An African state that developed along the upper reaches of the Nile c. 1000B.C.E.; conquered Egypt and ruled it for several centuries.</text>
<title>Mastodons</title><text>Prehistoric furry elephants, the retreat of big game animals like this one after an ice age lead to the increasing importance of agriculture, which catalyzed the movement and population boom among our species.</text>
<title>Mesolithic Age</title><text>The Middle Stone Age.12,000-8,000 BCE; ability to fashion stone tools and such improved greatly; made better weapons and cutting edges; had increased population growth accelerated producing more conflicts and wars;(Large amount of bone breaks and skull fractures.</text>
<title>Mesopotamia</title><text>First civilization located between the Tigris and Eurphrates Rivers in present day Iraq; term means "land between the rivers;" Sumerian culture, was WAY more fertile back then.</text>
<title>Mohenjo Daro</title><text>Along with Harappa, major urban complex of the Harappan civilization; laid out on planned grid pattern. Even had houses with running water.Language of the civilization has NOT been deciphered.</text>
<title>Monotheism</title><text>Belief in a single divine entity. The Israelite worship of Yahweh developed into an exclusive belief in one god, and this concept passed into Christianity and Islam.</text>
<title>Neolithic Age</title><text>The New stone age which went from about 8000 B.C to 3000 B.C. People who lived during this learned to polish stone tools, make pottery, grow crops, and raise animals.</text>
<title>Neolithic Revolution</title><text>This social revolution was also known as the New Stone Age where people changed from hunting and gathering food to domesticating animals and cultivating land as farmers. (Was actually very slow)</text>
<title>Nomads</title><text>cattle- and sheep-herding societies normally found on the fringes of civilized societies; commonly referred to as "barbarian" by civilized societies.</text>
<title>Oracles</title><text>Shamans or priests in Chinese society who foretold the future through interpretations of animal bones cracked by heat; inscriptions on bone led to Chinese writing.</text>
<title>P'an Ku</title><text>Mythic ancestor which ancient chinese said was their creator.</text>
<title>Paleolithic Age</title><text>The old stone age perio ending in 12,000 BCE, typified by the use of CRUDE stone tools and hunting and gathering for subsistence. Takes the majority of the 2 million plus years during which are species has existed. Homo Erctus first developed during this age.</text>
<title>Peking Man</title><text>A homo erectus skeleton about 1.7 million years old Found in Northern China near Beijeing; shows that people settled there more than 500,000 years ago.</text>
<title>Pharaoh</title><text>A kng of ancient Egypt, considered a god as well as a political and military leader.</text>
<title>Pyramids</title><text>Monumental architecture typical of Old Kingdom Egypt; used as burial sites for pharaohs.</text>
<title>Sargon of Akkad</title><text>A ancient Mesopotamian ruler who reigned approximately 2334-2279 BC, and was one of the earliest of the world's great empire builders, conquering all of southern Mesopotamia as well as parts of Syria, Anatolia, and Elam (western Iran). He established the region's first Semitic dynasty and was considered the founder of the Mesopotamian military tradition.</text>
<title>Shang</title><text>1st Dynasty in China had oracle bones, bronze casting, ancestor obsessed. Followed Xia</text>
<title>Skara Brae</title><text>A late Neolithic village in Northern Scotland(Orkeny Islands) discovered by archaeologists in the 1800s, Dates back to 1500 BCE. Special Storage areas for grain, sturdy housed, better conditions lead to higher birth rates and lower mortality rates at least when crop yeilds were high.</text>
<title>Slash and burn agriculture</title><text>Another name for shifting cultivation, so named because fields are cleared by slashing the vegetation and burning the debris. Used by non sedentary peoples who would farm for a couple of years and then leeave for a couple decades before codming back.</text>
<title>Speech Gene</title><text>What enabled our early anscestors to communicate better(beyond the sounds and gestures common to a number of animal groups), developed about 70,000 years earlier.</text>
<title>Sumerians</title><text>People who migrated into Mesopotamia ca. 4000 B.C.E.; created the first civilization within region; organized area into city-states. Also developed the cuneiform alphabet, the FIRST known case of human writing. Devloped a system of numbers based on 10, 60 , and 360, founded Astronomy and built massive Ziggurats.</text>
<title>Yellow River</title><text>River in China at a high plateau in Tibet. Loess soil carried by the river, gave river it's name, very fertile. "China's sorrow" when it had extensive flooding.The majority of ancient Chinese civilizations originated here.</text>
<title>Ziggurats</title><text>Massive towers usually associated with Mesopotamian temple complexes. Each city had a patron god that they prayed to and professional priests operated theses temples.</text>
<title>10,000 B.C.E.</title><text>the Neolithic Age began in what year?</text>
<title>135,000 -100,000 B.C.E</title><text>homo Sapiens Sapiens began to spread</text>
<title>14 billion B.C.E.</title><text>Some Scientists believe that the big bang occurred in what year?</text>
<title>1974</title><text>What year was Lucy discovered?</text>
<title>2 million B.C.E.</title><text>The Paleolithic Age began in what year?</text>
<title>2.5 million B.C.E.</title><text>The first traces of Homo habilis began in what year?</text>
<title>4 million-2.6 million B.C.E.</title><text>The Australopithecines Afarensis hominids lived between -----</text>
<title>4.5 billion B.C.E.</title><text>Some Scientists believe that the solar system and earth were formed in what year?</text>
<title>400,000 B.C.E.</title><text>Human language and Homo sapiens began in this year</text>
<title>7000-4000 B.C.E.</title><text>Agricultural communities were prominent beginning and ending when?</text>
<title>8000 B.C.E.</title><text>The Agricultural/ pastoral revolutions began in what year?</text>
<title>accelerator mass spectrometry</title><text>A method used by archaeologists to determine the age of various archaeological finds by separating smaller fossil samples and is used in Carbon 14 dating to get small samples of 14 atoms.</text>
<title>agriculture</title><text>seed selection and sowing of plants</text>
<title>Amerindans</title><text>Descendants from the Amurians and Mongoloids.</text>
<title>Amurians</title><text>The earliest migrating hunter-gatherers to cross to North America were from 50,000 to 20,000 years ago.</text>
<title>Anthropologists</title><text>scientist who study physical and cultural characteristics of people.</text>
<title>archaeologist</title><text>Scientists who study the remains of ancient people (both fossils and artifacts or man made objects)</text>
<title>artifacts</title><text>man- made objects from history, object made by human beings, either hand-made or mass-produced</text>
<title>Australopithecus Afarensis "Lucy"</title><text>Fossils found 3.9 million years ago and named Lucy. The earliest form of hominids. Found in 1974</text>
<title>B.C.E.</title><text>Before Common Error</text>
<title>bipedal</title><text>walking upright</text>
<title>C.E.</title><text>Common Era</text>
<title>carbon 14 dating</title><text>A method used by archaeologists to determine the age of various archaeological finds by measuring the amount of radioactive carbon left in an object.</text>
<title>Catal Huyuk</title><text>An early city with over 6000 inhabitants and houses and it was one of the earliest cities created by the Agricultural Revolution.</text>
<title>chronology</title><text>the recounting of the human story through time, arrangement of events in time</text>
<title>City-States</title><text>small and competing, each was centered on a large town which governed the countryside around it. Characterized by unceasing warfare over competition for control of irrigated land.</text>
<title>Cro- Magnon</title><text>capacity for emotion, sense of afterlife and art. Homo sapiens Sapien</text>
<title>Cultural Hearths</title><text>areas where civilizations first began that radiated the ideas, innovations, and ideologies that culturally transformed the world.</text>
<title>culture</title><text>learned behavior from a social organization based on unique survival techniques. Behavior patterns</text>
<title>dimorphic</title><text>a species wih two types of individuals, an example being Male and Females.</text>
<title>DNA</title><text>Deoxyribonucleic acid which contains the codes which reveal differences in everything with living cells.</text>
<title>Donald Johanson</title><text>Anthropologist who found bones that were 3 million years old and named his find Lucy; she was small and had walked on 2 legs.</text>
<title>fossils</title><text>the perserved trace, imprint, or remains of a plant or animal</text>
<title>girding</title><text>a technique to cut the bark around trees to kill them, let in sunlight, and keep out weeds.</text>
<title>Gondwanaland</title><text>Broke off from the large supercontinent about 200 million years ago and later formed the southern continents</text>
<title>Hadar</title><text>Where "Lucy" or Australopithecines Afarensis was discovered in East Africa</text>
<title>Hallen Cemi</title><text>10,000 years ago in southern turkey where the pig was first domesticated in food and the dog was domesticated from the wold.</text>
<title>hominid</title><text>primate that walks upright, has opposable thumbs, and possesses a large brain; only living members are humans</text>
<title>Homo Erectus</title><text>ate wide range of food, used fire and hand axe. Migrated widely 1.8 million years ago.</text>
<title>Homo Habilis</title><text>The first tool making hominid. 2.5 million years ago</text>
<title>Homo Sapiens sapiens</title><text>the newest human breed, originating c. 120,000 years ago, of which all humans in the world today are descendants</text>
<title>Homo Sapiens</title><text>400,000 years ago "consciously thinking human" appeared with complex frontal lobe which enabled them to think about the world, be more organized, and communicate. capacity for emotion.</text>
<title>horticulture</title><text>the use of hand tools to raise crops.</text>
<title>Huang Ho (Yellow River)</title><text>Where Chinese farmers began in 7000 B.C.</text>
<title>human language</title><text>ability to discuss the past, the future, real or imaginary things</text>
<title>hunter-gatherer</title><text>a type of society in which some hunted for food and others gathered fruits and vegetables but there was no structured agricultural system.</text>
<title>Ice Age</title><text>between 2 million and 11,000 years ago, the Pleistocene Age.</text>
<title>in situ</title><text>in its original place</text>
<title>Jarmo</title><text>(currently Iraq) one of the first places with sustainable agriculture.</text>
<title>Jericho</title><text>a village in Jordan near the north end of the Dead Sea. Founded by 7000 bce, one of the earliest cities.</text>
<title>Lascaux</title><text>A cave in southwestern France that contains Paleolithic painting</text>
<title>Laurasia</title><text>Broke off from the large supercontinent about 200 million years ago and later formed the northern continents</text>
<title>Louis Leakey</title><text>English paleontologist whose account of fossil discoveries in Tanzania changed theories of human evolution (1903-1972)</text>
<title>maize</title><text>one of the first cultivated crops, corn</text>
<title>Mary Leakey</title><text>English paleontologist (the wife of Louis Leakey) who discovered the Zinjanthropus skull that was 1,750,000 years old (1913-1996)</text>
<title>Mongoloids</title><text>The most recent hunter-gatheres to cross to north America</text>
<title>Multiregional Model</title><text>No single origin for humans
Instead, gene flow and repeated pop. movements and intermixing is extensive
Transmission of alleles among individuals leads to appearance of modern H. sapiens
Neandertals contribute genes to living human populations</text>
<title>Neanderthal</title><text>Homo Sapien which had capacity for emotion and possessed sense of afterlife.</text>
<title>Neolithic</title><text>8000BCE New Stone Age</text>
<title>New Stone Age</title><text>8000BCE Neolithic Age</text>
<title>Old Stone Age</title><text>Paleolithic age 10,000 BCE</text>
<title>Olduvai Gorge</title><text>one of the most important sights in the world from fossil evidence of human origin. In Africa.</text>
<title>Out of Africa model</title><text>Describes that modern humans evolved in Africa between 200,000 and 150,000 years ago, migrated out to colonize the world and replaced earlier hominid species</text>
<title>Paleolithic</title><text>Old Stone Age; 10,000 BCE</text>
<title>paleontologist</title><text>Scientists who study fossils of plants and animals</text>
<title>Pangaea</title><text>Scientists theorize tat there was once one supercontinent called _______, that later broke into all other continents.</text>
<title>pastoralism</title><text>the domestication of animal, coincided with the development of agriculture.</text>
<title>plate tectonics</title><text>A theory about rigid plates forming the outer layer of the earth's surface that float on the magma or molten rock near the earth's core. They are believed to have pushed continents apart and when they collide they form mountains and mountain lines.</text>
<title>prehistory</title><text>A time before written history</text>
<title>Private Property</title><text>a concept originating from the neolithic revolution which has since defined human society and the accumulation of goods.</text>
<title>rice paddy farming</title><text>Planting rice seedlings n standing water, one of the first forms of agriculture.</text>
<title>root crops</title><text>manioc, taro,cassava, and yams are fruits cultivated by the women of the community and are called ____.</text>
<title>Semitic</title><text>the language family which led to the development of Arabic and Hebrew.</text>
<title>slash-and-burn</title><text>a system that allowed farmers to grow grain in places where it did not grow naturally by burning dead trees so the ashes could improve fertility. Requires farmers to move every 5-6 years.</text>
<title>society</title><text>A group of people with a similar culture, environment, language and set of rules.</text>
<title>Tehuacan Valley</title><text>First evidence of maize or corn was found here in 4500 to 4700 years ago</text>
</data>